Go
ahead and get started.
So before we dive
in, thank you, Amber,
for that wonderful introduction.
I also just want to give a
little background as well about
who I am and why I'll be
talking about what
I'm talking about today.
So my name is Dana Frayne.
I'm at the University of Oxford
as a master's student and
specifically I'm at the Internet
Institute so I spend my days
thinking about how the internet
essentially affects society,
particularly in relation to
how the internet
is accessible online.
Before coming to Oxford,
I was already quite interested in
digital accessibility so I don't
think it surprised any of my
friends or people who know me
that I wanted to study this for
my master's thesis.
In particular, like Amber said,
I worked as a freelance digital
accessibility consultant and one
of my projects working on the
American Civil Liberty--Civil
Liberties Union homepage
so that it was accessible
was really great.
So currently finishing up the
master's degree at Oxford and
I'm gonna be talking about some
of my thesis findings today as
well as, you know, some of my
personal experiences working
in digital accessibility.
So, as sort of the agenda for
the talk today, first I'm gonna
kind of give a overview of
my research goals and then
transition to a brief discussion
of the theoretical frameworks
that are kind of
driving that question.
Then I'm going to be examining
briefly the method I use and
then the findings
and future directions.
So, the main takeaway from my
background earlier, is that I am
coming from both a practical
perspective on one side but then
also theoretical, more academic,
perspective and I mentioned my
course work at Oxford and that
involves a thesis which, one of
the main requirements is having
a research question, so on the
screen now is mine which says:
"What is the role of social
norms in the implementation of
digital accessibility practices
in the technology industry?"
So, with this question, I
was essentially working toward
figuring out and observing the
different norms that operate
when people
are trying to put
digital accessibility policies
into practice.
So one question I got in is
why study this particular topic?
And there are a few reasons,
the first one being that I have
found there is a gap in the
academic literature regarding
social norms and digital
accessibility, partially because
there is not, I'd say, a great
deal of academic research that
sort of publicly exists
squarely on the topic
of digital accessibility.
Furthermore, the research
that does exist is often--
it can be siloed into
niche topics and circles so
sometimes there is a risk of
being sort of put into
echo chambers of people who
already feel quite strongly about
digital accessibility, and then
you know, for the research that
does exist, the data
does not always cover the
aspect of implementation so
particularly in the technology
industry, sometimes I've found
that the viewpoints can be a bit
disconnected between, you
know, industry versus academia.
So one of the goals of my
research is to sort of
merge these two viewpoints
together, not that they exist
completely separately
but that was one of the goals.
And then, secondly, or
second, digital accessibility is
highly, highly interdisciplinary
which I'm sure a lot of people
tuning in can relate to this
idea that, you know, to work in
digital accessibility
sometimes it feels like
you specialize in
a lot of different areas
from the technical part to the
legal part to the theory part
and there are lots of
different parts to it.
So I--that was another reason
I wanted to kind of address
social norms because they
touch on all those areas.
And then finally, the third
reason which is the main reason
I wanted to study this is
my main personal experiences
with digital accessibility
and working in
digital accessibility,
I feel like I have
personally experienced these
social norms that I'm going to
talk about and my hope in
bringing them up today is that,
maybe someone tuning in
will also have experienced this
and I think,
as a community of people
who care about digital accessibility,
it's important to
kind of rally around,
advocating for digital accessibility.
So, that's kind of the goal with
my research and the goal that
I'm--that I have today and I
think that's partially why
events like these are so
great because it brings
the community together.
So, moving on into the research
itself, I'm not going to spend a
great deal of time defining
theories and frameworks but I've
included the major theorist in
parentheses here on the screen,
along with, you know,
their associated theories.
So if you're interested and
wanna learn more about anything
I'm talking about, I have a list
of references at the end if you
wanna check it--check out
these theories further.
But the first one says the
social model of disability and
Mike Oliver and Tom Shakespeare
are two of the
leading architects
of this framework.
And it has its foundations in
the United Kingdom, sort of the
activist grassroots movement
when there was a big push from
the medical model of
disability to the social model.
And the conception of the social
model was founded in
this idea that social barriers
blocked participation
in social groups.
So this is a problem because,
you know, this
potentially could lead to
obstacles for people with
disabilities to
lead a fulfilling
and high quality of life.
And I mention this here,
primarily because
the social model is now
the primary mode
in which scholars studying
the topic of disability
utilize and it's therefore,
the model that drives this research.
Just gonna take a
sip real quick.
Okay, well, so, moving on to
the next theory I have listed.
So, intersectionality from
Kimberlé Crenshaw who is a
brilliant feminist scholar.
She coined and is one of
the lead architects
of this concept,
intersectionality,
which essentially means
the aspects of identity
are fluid as opposed to
concrete, single artifacts
of one's self
and self-presentation.
And in other words, you know,
intersectionality is sort of
this idea that
multiple identities like--
dimensions of identity
like race, socioeconomic status,
gender, ability, you know, so on,
they deserve an equitable weight
when kind of considering
identity politics.
So, based on this
cornerstone theory, it's--
I'd say it's fair to suggest that
disability is intertwined with
a lot of different
dimensions of identity,
so when talking
about this research,
I feel like it's really important
to acknowledge that
disability doesn't essentially
exist in a vacuum.
It's, you know, there are lots
of parts of identity to think
about so I just wanna
note up front that I try to
incorporate intersectionality
into my research
and just general life approach.
And then moving on to
the next framework,
the narrative self,
which is proposed by
and really led by
this philosopher named
Marya Schechtman
and essentially
the narrative self
presents this idea that a
cohesive collection of
one's memories and
ideas about the self
come together to present,
you know, the self presentation
so, in other words,
whenever I hear someone say,
"This is, you know,
on brand for this person,"
I sort of think of this theory
because it's essentially
Schechtman's idea that
presentations of the self,
it's a collection of different
memories and artifacts
that are shared online.
So, with these
theories in mind,
I'm gonna transition to a
discussion of the findings
and the process of
gathering the findings.
So for my thesis, I conducted
a series of interviews
with accessibility experts
and practitioners
and it's important to note
that the primary framework
that I used was the
postmodernist viewpoint
because it was really,
you know, I related to it a lot
because it emphasized
the nuanced nature of
the interviewer and the
interviewee relationship,
along with the broader
philosophical belief that
multiple versions of the truth
can exist in society.
Also I was conscientious about
the broader postmodernist push
in academia to adhere to
equitable sampling practices
in order to better represent
diverse experiences
in the findings.
I'm just gonna--okay, sorry.
I feel like I'm battling a bit
of a cold coming on,
so, sorry about that.
Okay, back to it.
So, the second point was that
just another minor note
is that one of my concerns
with the interview method was
sometimes people can say
interviews purely produce
descriptive findings but
I would kind of push back
against this idea in the
sense that it's--
interviews are useful,
particularly in sociological research,
to uncover social norms
and some perspectives
that can sometimes be hidden.
So now I'm gonna shift to a
discussion of the findings and,
to do that, I am going to
read off a brief scenario.
Okay, so, the--I'm gonna
read what's onscreen now.
So, imagine that you're
working at a company
that is launching a
new website tomorrow.
You primarily work
as a product designer,
but you're considered
the "go-to" person
for digital accessibility
in the company.
You don't personally work on the team
that's preparing for launch,
but a manager
from a different team
knows that you know
a lot about accessibility.
This manager emails
you to ask, "Hey!
Can you make the
website accessible before
the launch tomorrow?"
Less than a day is
not a lot of time
to make a website accessible,
but you really want to help
because no one else
in the company
seems to know about the
specific accessibility guidelines.
So you ask the manager,
"Sure, but, you know,
what has already been done
for accessibility?"
They respond by saying,
"We only just remembered
because we don't want to
get in trouble with
an inaccessible site.
If you could just check
the boxes for the basic
accessibility criteria before
launch, that would be great!"
Okay, so let's
dissect this for a moment.
You know, I cannot see the
comments right now
but I would venture to ask
if anyone listening or watching
has ever experienced a
scenario similar to this.
I know bits and pieces of this.
I certainly have,
but essentially
I wanted to share
this fictional scenario
that's sort of drawn
from some truths
that I experienced
because it represents
all three of the social norms
that I'm gonna talk about today.
So, the three social norms have,
like I mentioned in the agenda,
are--so the first one's
compliance culture
which I think hopefully
a lot of people find interesting.
And then the second one is
valuation of accessibility work
and then the third one is
educational opportunities.
So now I'm going to transition
into a discussion of
each of these social norms
by talking about what they are,
how they play a role
in digital accessibility,
and then why they exist.
So, first, compliance culture.
In relation to digital
accessibility is a concept
that's discussed
a great deal in actually
Professor Sarah
Lewthwaite's research.
She focuses on studying
the pedagogy of
digital accessibility.
So her research is
really fascinating and
if you're interested in learning
more about compliance culture,
I would definitely recommend
looking up some of her articles.
Or you can email me
afterwards and
I can send you some as well.
But anyways, as a concept,
compliance culture
is this idea that
digital accessibility
is only a set of
rules to abide by
as opposed to a genuine
approach to accessibility
that reinforces
creativity and continuity.
And I also wanna note here
before moving forward
that just the name itself,
compliance culture,
can potentially be
misleading in the sense
when I first heard about it,
I was a bit confused because
on its own I'd argue that
compliance is a good thing,
complying with policies
shows that people care,
but the main difference
between compliance
versus compliance culture is,
it graduates from
being this practice to an
attitude and set of behaviors
making it more aligned
with a social norm.
So that's when it becomes
more of an issue
and this relates to
digital accessibility because
in interviews with
digital accessibility practitioners
working in the technology industry,
there was this repeated theme
about the ongoing effort
to kind of stymie
the practices of compliance culture
because compliance culture
can block sustainability of
continued accessibility practices,
particularly because
it can sort of stand
as a road block between
working towards creativity,
innovation, and continuous
accessibility process
as opposed to this
static, rigid, set of rules.
So, going back to the scenario I
presented, I wanted to highlight
this particular part that
sort of exemplifies this idea.
So on the screen
it says the quote,
"We only just remembered
because we don't want
to get in trouble
with an inaccessible site."
This is coming from the
perspective of the manager.
"If you could just check
the boxes for the basic
accessibility criteria before
launch, that would be great."
So, this certainly has elements
of compliance culture,
in particular there's
the sense of urgency.
"We only just remembered."
This is a problem because
accessibility should certainly
be a--in an ideal world,
accessibility should be
incorporated from the very
beginning of the product
development process for
a multitude of reasons,
but in particular,
one of those reasons
is that it prevents sort of this
last-minute stressful time of
trying to make something
accessible really quick because
it sort of changes from this,
process of, okay,
"how can we make this
user experience a good one,"
as opposed to, okay,
"how can we quickly just meet
the very basic accessibility criteria
so we don't get in trouble?"
You know, those are two
different--there are
significant differences
between those two approaches,
and it's sort of where
compliance culture
is really relevant.
So before moving on to
the next social norm,
I just wanted to take
a moment to reflect on
some reasons why I think
compliance culture exists
and regarding the
theoretical concerns,
I think this represents
sort of a quick fix mentality
in the technology industry
because from my experience--
from my experience
working in tech,
I have found that there are
pressures to work quickly
and launch things quickly.
And, you know, I think
that's good for innovation.
However, I think in order
for accessibility to exist
in that sort of
very fast process,
it's essential that it's an
ongoing consideration
as opposed to, okay,
let's look at this
right before we launch.
And then, another--something
also that, you know, I've been
thinking about, and some other
scholars in this space, like
Professor [name unclear] and
Professor Sarah Lewthwaite also
have produced research on,
also other great scholars,
but essentially
there's this debate
where sometimes the
definitions of accessibility,
the policies of accessibility,
can be quite broad.
So sometimes it can feel
difficult to know exactly what
to do in order to make this
something accessible,
when if someone doesn't
know how to make something
accessible, which I talk further
about in the upcoming norms.
And then, the last two points:
practical constraints,
so again, time constraints
are a consideration,
and the availability
of resources.
So, again with this scenario,
this scenario presented,
trying to make something
accessible in a very short
amount of time and there's
putting all the responsibility
on one person,
can be quite difficult.
You know, the
scenario didn't mention
how expansive
the product was
so that can again
be quite challenging.
So, moving on to the
next main social norm.
I wanted to talk about
the attitude and behaviors
associated with the valuation
of digital accessibility work.
And here, I wanna kind
of pause for clarity.
When I say, "valuation,"
I am talking about both
the financial and
opportunity cost
associated with the work
of digital accessibility.
So, the first point I want to
address is that the values
associated with this
digital accessibility work
are quite varied based on
industry and location
and a lot of different factors,
and also going back to
Kimberlé Crenshaw's
theory of intersectionality,
there are a lot of factors
at play with cost and value,
so it's--so I wanna make sure
I clarify here that
it doesn't exist in a vacuum.
However, there is this trend
that I noticed in my research
and personal experience
that this, it is not always--
accessibility work
is not always
compensated fairly
in my opinion
and one of the
most common ways
that this manifests is
and maybe some people
watching or listening
have had this experience
where people who are experts
or knowledgeable, even,
in digital accessibility practices
are called on to do the
work of multiple people
and so, by this,
I mean that sometimes,
digital accessibility
is sort of viewed as maybe
a side project or optional
and in this scenario,
this person is sort of--
it's not clear whether
this person's going
to be compensated
or recognized properly
for their work.
And the second point I wanna
make--the second point I wanna
make--want to make about
this is that the valuation of
accessibility work, often it can
be--it can co-exist alongside
this phenomenon of being
siloed into an accessibility
maintenance role,
even, you know,
when the job description
doesn't call for it.
And sort of, by this, I mean
that accessibility work
requires flexibility as I
mentioned earlier
with compliance culture,
accessibility in my view
is a continuous
ongoing process.
So when it's viewed through
a lens of being optional
or not as valued,
that really puts a strain
on the whole process because
it doesn't necessarily give
the space that's needed
for digital accessibility
to really prosper
and be successful.
So returning to the
example presented earlier,
the way this issue of value
presents itself is through
the following quote
on the screen, which says,
"A manager from
a different team
knows that you know
a lot about accessibility."
So, reflecting on this
for a moment,
the way the social norm
manifested in this scenario
is that, you know,
it's not clear from this scenario
that accessibility is
considered a part of
this person's usual accessibilities.
It's noted that the
person is knowledgeable;
however it's also
noted that they are
primarily a product designer
so you can kind of assume
that they, you know,
their whole job isn't
focused on accessibility
which presents a different
scenario but it's not clear--
the main point I'm
trying to make here is
it's not clear whether
this person is
going to be compensated
for their time working on
this accessibility process.
It's sort of presented as a
favor as opposed to, you know,
you're gonna get
recognition for your work,
which is really, really
important in terms of value.
And then, the other point
I wanna mention
which is not specifically
mentioned in the slide
but the general attitude,
sort of, of this manager
kind of signals to me
a lack of recognition
for the accessibility process
as again being
continuous process that
should be incorporated
from the very beginning
when possible.
So, this sort of leads
to the question of
why do these
valuation challenges
exist in the first place.
Well, in my opinion,
the answer is
quite complicated,
so it--I'd argue that
there are a lot of
parallels that exist
with the broader
disability rights movement
and, you know,
I'm looking at the time.
For sake of time, it's sort of
hard to dive into that now, but
if you wanna talk
more about that,
definitely send me an email
and I'd love to talk about it but,
essentially, the, you know,
the main relationship here is
that I'd argue that
the struggle with value
is part of a overarching,
broader perspective
that exists in the
technology industry
where stakeholders
don't necessarily recognize
accessibility work with the
value of other disciplines,
other technical skills.
And, you know, this is a problem
because, you know, this can
manifest in different ways
where maybe someone
doesn't get promoted or
recognized in the same way that,
you know, other people do
because if, you know, the
employers don't recognize, okay,
accessibility work, it's very
significant, it's important,
and it's critical to a
product having a strong useable
experience that, you know, that
can create significant problems.
And then the second part of
this where, you know, sometimes
accessibility can sort of be
viewed through this lens of
volunteering where,
as I mentioned earlier,
it's unclear whether this person
in this scenario is going to be
properly compensated
for their time and,
if this is just a favor
that doesn't really--
that doesn't really
help with accessibility
being properly recognized.
And last point I wanna make
about this before moving to the
next social norm is I
personally struggle with this.
You know, and maybe people
tuning in as well really
struggle because as someone
who's really passionate about
digital accessibility, I'm so,
you know, I'm really happy when
people express
interest in it, even if it is
last-minute or, you know,
even if it is challenging.
So I'm definitely more
inclined to I wanna help
as much as I can but that can
also present a challenge when,
even if I help, if my work
isn't valued in the same way,
it can be
quite frustrating.
So, on that note, moving to the
third and final social norm that
I'm going to discuss today,
is the specific attitudes and
behaviors that people face
when first entering the
field of digital accessibility,
specifically in relation to
educational opportunities
for accessibility.
Okay, so a recurring theme
was that, the offerings for
digital accessibility education
are not particularly robust
in comparison to other skills,
other technical skills in
design and development.
And the repercussions for these
lack of accessibility resources
is widespread and
I kind of wanna
focus this section on
a couple of key points but
one of the points
I have listed onscreen
is that there is no one pathway
to studying digital accessibility,
which on the one hand
is good because, you know,
I personally relate to
this idea that I have
picked up lessons about
digital accessibility on the job
which helps in terms of
learning practical ways
to apply accessibility
but at the same time,
if one doesn't have
access to work opportunities,
to learn, it can make things
quite difficult to gather
digital accessibility,
you know, specific practices,
which leads to kind of the third
point I have here, which is
there is, I have found, as well
as in my research, that there
are pretty significant
differences that exist between,
you know, learning about
accessibility from this
theoretical perspective
versus implementing it.
And there are lots of,
I was, before moving, I did
wanna mention, you know, there
are lots of great resources and
classes out there and, you know,
if you have any favorite classes
or things I would love to
see them in the comments.
But I wanted to note,
in terms of mainstream
educational options, I would say
there are not any major degrees
that specify in
digital accessibility.
There are minor certificates,
online classes which are great,
but I, you know, I think if,
for example, if there was
a master's degree in
digital accessibility
I would totally want
to enroll in that,
but from my search,
there is not,
and that can, you know,
that is sort of a challenge
in and of itself because
stakeholders at universities and
educational programs
do not always recognize
accessibility work with the
value of other disciplines.
So one way this
manifests specifically is
from people I've talked to,
accessibility can be
incorporated into computer
science classes or sometimes
even have a whole course
dedicated to accessibility
which is great, but I feel like and--
I feel like this is
a common feeling but
accessibility is so expansive and,
like I mentioned in the previous slide,
it's hard to sort of
narrow it down versus
into theory
versus practice,
so I feel like if there was more
room and more recognition of
digital accessibility in these
mainstream educational places
and spaces, I should say,
that would lead to
more widespread education.
Okay, so through this example,
I--
the social norm sort of
manifested through the quote,
"You primarily work as
a product designer,
but you're considered the,"
quote, "'go-to' person for
digital accessibility
in the company."
So, sort of from what I've
gathered, particularly at
smaller companies and startups,
it's sort of not uncommon for
there to be sort of this,
you know, "go-to" person for
accessibility which is fine
but I think, you know,
I think in an ideal world, it
would be amazing if, you know,
every person had at least a
foundation in accessibility
because, you know, accessibility
doesn't exist in this vacuum.
It's not just, you know,
an engineering concern,
design concern, content concern,
you know, a recruiting concern.
You know, it really exists
widespread so I think
it's not particularly fair for the,
you know, responsibility to be with
one person so sort of
one way to combat this is for
education to be more widespread
and at the university training
crash course level, accessibility,
more accessibility knowledge
would be good.
But employers can also
have a role in this when,
you know, when new employees
are being onboarded,
be great if accessibility is
discussed and acknowledged
and specific practices for
that company are shared.
So it's not sort of
reliant on one person.
Okay, so wrapping up, we're
about 35 minutes so I think
about 5 to 10 more minutes
and then I'd love to take any
questions for a bit.
But the first future direction
is, I think it's really
important for people working in
digital accessibility to work
towards combating solutionism,
so I should say here,
solutionism is sort of a concept
designed by this theorist,
Morozov, who I cite more in
the references but, essentially,
solutionism is this idea
that there is a goal of
solving problems, as opposed to
actually addressing the
complexity of
problems that exist
in the technology industry.
And I think this is
quite relevant to digital
accessibility because
digital accessibility,
as I mentioned,
is quite complex.
Not only is it an ongoing
process but it's very
widespread and
interdisciplinary,
so it's critical that it's
viewed in that light.
It's not just ticking the
specific boxes of policy,
but it's recognized
as a comprehensive,
widespread consideration.
So some concrete ways
to address this would be
making sure that
every person in
a company or a product team,
is knowledgeable about
at least the basics of
accessibility but also,
consistently testing with
users to make sure,
okay, this product, testing
with users with disabilities
so there's an open
line of communication
and that you're
recognizing that,
okay, the goal is to make this
a good usability experience,
not just to, you know,
tick off some boxes.
Then the second
future direction is
there's really a critical
need to increase the
value of accessibility work.
And like I said earlier,
this is not, you know,
there are certainly
exceptions to this.
However, I would say,
a trend that I am
kind of concerned about is,
it's not always--
the value of accessibility work
is not always, I think,
given the recognition
that it deserves.
And people, stakeholders
in the tech industry,
certainly play a role
in this but, you know, also,
anyone on a product team
just advocating for accessibility,
calling out the work,
supporting, you know,
people who also
work in accessibility,
is a great way to address this.
And then, finally, which is
probably the future direction
that I'm most excited about,
is this starting point
that I wanna suggest is that
integrating creativity into the
conversation is really a, you
know, a great way, I think, to
draw greater interest
and respect of digital
accessibility--greater
interest and respect
in the technology industry.
And, you know, there are a lot
of great projects in this space
which I can also
share links to
if you wanna
email me afterwards.
But essentially,
creativity is a
great vehicle for
approaching digital access.
And sort of to wrap up,
I wanted to say
stakeholder changes are critical.
Creative approaches are great,
and then collaboration in the
accessibility community
is also really important,
which is why events like this
are really exciting and
I'm really excited to be
a part of this and connect
and virtually meet people
who also really care
about digital access,
so that's it.
These are my references.
The slides are available at the
WordPress Accessibility site
if you wanna
go through the references.
You can also send me an email.
My email's
dana.frayne@gmail.com,
and also my Twitter handle
is dana_frayne.
I just want to thank quickly,
you know, Joe Dolson and the
whole WordPress Accessibility
team for having me and I'm happy
to take any questions.
Well,
thank you so much, Dana.
We do have a
couple of questions.
The first one is: "Do you
consider that the multiple
truths viewpoint is reflected in
the fact that there's frequently
no one true solution to web
accessibility questions?"
That's a
great question.
So it is something that I
think about because
I totally, you know, align
with this idea that digital
accessibility is a fluid social
construction and, by that,
I mean, accessibility
means something different,
I think, to each person.
So I really, you know, hesitate,
kind of, when, you know,
accessibility is defined
as, you know, X, Y, and Z.
I think it really is dependent
on local context and
again tying back to this
concept of intersectionality,
it's really important, I think,
to acknowledge that
accessibility doesn't
exist in a vacuum.
It sort of touches on these
different dimensions of identity,
so I certainly think that
there's a connection there
and thanks for pointing that
out for who asked that question.
So the next question
is "What would you like to see
done with your research?
Do you have goals for it?"
Yes, this is
another great question.
I mean, I think, hopefully, I,
you know, would love to publish
my research in a academic
article but, you know, that is a
pretty intense process, but I,
you know, it's something
that I hope to do.
And also next year, I hope to,
fingers crossed, I'll be able to
go to Morocco with
the Fulbright program
to do a research grant
where I can sort of
continue this research
and approach it from a
different lens of studying
digital accessibility
within a specific context,
as opposed to this research today.
I recognize that it's quite broad,
so I think it would be exciting
to sort of go at it
from a different angle
and be more specific.
Do you--are you
hoping that it'll inspire
certain actions either at the
government level or among people
who work in digital
accessibility on a daily basis?
Sorry, can you
repeat that real quick?
Oh, I was just
following up on that question.
Are you hoping that your
research would inspire certain
actions either at the government
level or with those of us that
work in accessibility
on a daily basis?
Well, sure, yeah.
I mean, I think
that would be great.
You know, I think the one,
main takeaway that I
really hope my research can
share is that I think, you know,
my personal experience
working in digital accessibility
sometimes it can feel
a bit, you know, lonely if,
going back to that
scenario where there's
one person on this team
who's considered the expert.
I feel like, you know, when I
was conducting this research I
think it made me feel quite an
appreciation for the community
and, you know, knowing that
there are lots of people all
over the world who really care
about digital accessibility and,
if you're working on this
project, you know, you're
not--if you experience
something, there's probably
someone somewhere who is
experiencing something similar
so if you can sort of find, you
know, reach out to the community
and make connections
and feel the sense of
camaraderie, I think
that would be something.
I hope that is inspired
through this research.
Yeah, no, that
is definitely something with
WordPress, right?
And accessibility as well.
We're very big on
community building, so.
There's a question here: "Do
you have ideas about ways to get
people excited about
the creative aspects of
accessibility instead of viewing
it as a maintenance task?"
Yes, certainly.
I mean, I think--let's see,
how to structure this.
Well, you know, one example that
I wanna, you know, I think would
be great to draw attention to is
there is this project called
Alt Text as Poetry.
And I, you know, the specific
authors kind of, I can't recall
them off the top of my head but
hopefully, I can, you know, add
them in the--add a
link in the chat.
Shannon Finnigan?
Yes, yeah, yeah.
And then, so I think this is,
you know, a really brilliant
project because the, you know,
they really exemplify how,
you know, alt text is can--
some people can view it as,
you know, the static,
rigid practice but it's,
in a way, I feel like it is
sort of a poetic form,
and they really, you know,
encapsulate that and I think
projects like that
are really exciting.
I know there's also, you know, a
movement in the 'zine world to
sort of push for digital
accessibility and sort of,
you know, when there are
artistic projects like that,
that I think that can be
really exciting, and
it's something that excites me.
Yeah, I think we have
time for one more question
and it's actually my question.
I'm wondering how do you propose
to increase the valuation of
digital accessibility so, you
know, we see a lot of almost
like fear-based arguments for
accessibility and I'm wondering
if you have thoughts on ways to
increase that valuation that's
maybe not fear-based, or do
you feel like, looking at the
social, that that is
just the way to go?
That's my--I
mean, that's a great question.
I feel like it's something I
sort of debate internally as
well because, I mean, I think
we do live in sort of a call-out
culture where fear is sort
of--can be a driving force.
However, I think, you know,
that's not the only way
to go about it.
I think, you know, grassroots
activism and sort of going back
to, you know, the social model
of disability, I'd say that the
grassroots kind of tactics used
in activism can also be used for
digital accessibility at, you
know, in this idea
of increasing value.
And then also I wanna say,
you know, there is strength in
numbers and I think--I guess
I've mentioned it a lot now, but
I would say, you know, but I
keep saying it 'cause I think it's
really important, this idea
of community and, you know,
fostering support, you know,
between different accessibility
experts and practitioners is
really important to show
we are, you know, a
strong group of people
who are [unintelligible]
like numerous group of people
who, you know, really care
and wanna advocate
for digital accessibility.
Well, thank you.
Yeah, thank
you for having me.
Yes,
so thank you, everyone,
for attending this WP--